<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-19T01:25:42-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aperture Science Trash Fire Cloning Initiative</title><subtitle>I have no idea how to use jekyll, but I&apos;m about to find out.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Precision Villager House Detonator</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/12/22/Villager-House-Detonator.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Precision Villager House Detonator" /><published>2023-12-22T18:10:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-22T18:10:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/12/22/Villager-House-Detonator</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/12/22/Villager-House-Detonator.html">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I worked with some friends on a small Minecraft SMP server to take out someone who liked to combat log. While I’m not proud of the circumstances, I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; proud of this small piece of precision engineering. The combat logger in question lived in a small villager house, so I designed this precision explosive to destroy the house with minimal collateral damage. It was made to be hidden under the house, so there are no above-ground components, and it was made to be efficient, using 5 pieces of TNT as efficiently as I could manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/villager_house_exploder/design.png&quot; alt=&quot;Redstone design for villager house detonator&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Precision Villager House Detonator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/villager_house_exploder/design_cutaway.png&quot; alt=&quot;Redstone design for villager house detonator (cutaway view)&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Precision Villager House Detonator, cutaway view. Closest TNT piece and glass to viewer removed to show the restone torch that triggers the primary charge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is relatively simple, but was refined through many trials. The four pieces of TNT on the bottom make up the primary charge, which blows up the bottom of the house. The single piece of TNT on the top is the secondary charge, which is launched up by the primary charge, and destroys the top of the house. The secondary charge is lit 4 ticks after the primary charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/villager_house_exploder/diagram_excalidraw.png&quot; alt=&quot;Excalidraw diagram of villager house detonator&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Diagram drawn in Excalidraw demonstrating the action of the detonator.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As demonstrated below, this design provides a minor improvement over a standard untimed TNT charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/villager_house_exploder/exploded_house_regular.png&quot; alt=&quot;House detonated with a standard untimed charge&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 4: A small villager house detonated using an untimed charge of 6 pieces of TNT. The roof is relatively intact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/villager_house_exploder/exploded_house_precision.png&quot; alt=&quot;House detonated with a precision timed charge&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Figure 5: A small villager house detonated using the timed precision charge detailed in this article with only 5 pieces of TNT. The roof is less intact than the previous image.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further research is necessary to create a more modular or scalable version of this design, to create one that more thoroughly destroys the roof, and to create one capable of destroying larger sizes of villager house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assets&quot;&gt;Assets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Litematica schematic for this design is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/villager_house_exploder/precision_villager_house_exploder.litematic&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="video-games" /><category term="minecraft" /><summary type="html">A few years ago, I worked with some friends on a small Minecraft SMP server to take out someone who liked to combat log. While I’m not proud of the circumstances, I am proud of this small piece of precision engineering. The combat logger in question lived in a small villager house, so I designed this precision explosive to destroy the house with minimal collateral damage. It was made to be hidden under the house, so there are no above-ground components, and it was made to be efficient, using 5 pieces of TNT as efficiently as I could manage.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accountability with AI</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/20/ai-accountability.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accountability with AI" /><published>2023-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/20/ai-accountability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/20/ai-accountability.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is a public version of my comments submitted to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.regulations.gov/document/OSTP-TECH-2023-0007-0001&quot;&gt;US government’s request for information on artificial intelligence&lt;/a&gt;. As such, it’s primarily plain text and contains little formatting, as it was submitted as plain text. The examples are simplified to be as comprehensive to the layman as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, the government makes the request for comments inordinately hard to find. Tarah Wheeler has an excellent post on how hard it is to find &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tarah.org/2023/06/10/yes-but-how-do-i-submit-a-comment-on-how-unintuitive-the-comment-submission-process-is/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comments-to-the-office-of-science-and-technology-policy&quot;&gt;Comments to the Office of Science and Technology Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My comment is specifically about safety measures that must be taken in the development of AI technology to ensure that people’s rights and safety are protected in an equitable manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If no other part of this comment is read, it’s imperative that this one thing be communicated: &lt;strong&gt;Computers cannot be held accountable, and therefore must not make decisions unsupervised.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to complicated issues involving the nature of problem-solving computer programs, computers may come to conclusions that seem reasonable to them but are unacceptable or dangerous to people. To prevent them from automatically acting upon these conclusions, it’s imperative that a person review and approve suggested actions provided by computer assistance before they are enacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the example of a computer system assigning dorm rooms at a college. Imagine that it evaluates how well matched people are to their preferred rooms using a score, and will select the highest scoring arrangement. If one person is in a room that they prefer, the arrangement gets 1 point. We wouldn’t want someone in a wheelchair to be in an upstairs room that they couldn’t get to, so we might assign this situation -1000 points. Unfortunately, this would let the computer select a situation where 1002 people get their preferred rooms and 1 person in a wheelchair gets an inaccessible room, over a situation where 1 person gets the room they want, and everyone else gets an acceptable but not preferred room. If the computer had no oversight, it might deem this an acceptable solution, and nobody would realize until a disabled person tried to move into their second floor room on the first day of school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there remains the possibility of purposeful accountability dodging. &lt;strong&gt;Humans must be responsible for the decisions of computers they create and run.&lt;/strong&gt; Otherwise, unscrupulous parties could outsource any unethical decision to a computer, and completely avoid liability for any damage caused. For this reason, it’s of paramount importance that usage of AI tools not diminish one’s culpability (legal or otherwise) in making poor decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="ai" /><category term="politics" /><summary type="html">This post is a public version of my comments submitted to the US government’s request for information on artificial intelligence. As such, it’s primarily plain text and contains little formatting, as it was submitted as plain text. The examples are simplified to be as comprehensive to the layman as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Artificing with your DM in DnD 5e</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/19/Artificing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artificing with your DM in DnD 5e" /><published>2023-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/19/Artificing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/19/Artificing.html">&lt;p&gt;In DnD 5e, Artificer has one of the loosest job descriptions of any class. Depending on both your playstyle and your DM’s, this can lend incredible flexibility or cause a decent amount of strife. To ensure things go as smoothly as they can, there are a few things you should keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-experienced-is-your-dm&quot;&gt;How experienced is your DM?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DnD 5e is complicated and has a lot of rules, and the information in the core books is not well-indexed for finding specific mechanics or rules. If your DM is not thoroughly familiar with the mechanics of 5e, you may need to help them figure out the intended interactions of specific pieces of your kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the information about these interactions on hand will prevent having to pause the session while your DM digs around to find it. If your DM is very new or not at all familiar with the mechanics of 5e, you may want to reconsider playing artificer in their domain until they become more experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-dms-style&quot;&gt;What’s your DM’s style?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to know how your DM likes to build encounters, and what kind they like to build. Do they favor combat or roleplay? Open-world exploration, or dungeon crawls? How much will they railroad the party into the plot? How open are they to unconventional solutions for plot problems? These are all extremely important, because they determine how your DM will expect you to work with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5e-does-not-have-a-hard-magic-system&quot;&gt;5e &lt;em&gt;does not have&lt;/em&gt; a hard magic system!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know what hard and soft magic systems are, Wikipedia has a short section on it &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandon_Sanderson#Sanderson&apos;s_Laws_of_Magic&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it bluntly, the magic system in DnD is not internally consistent. The real world reason is likely decades of technical debt, and I’m not enough of a scholar on DnD to know if there’s an in-universe reason. Because of this, it can be difficult or impossible to extrapolate out rules to their logical ends in the same way that hard magic systems or science do. (Much to my dismay as a science enjoyer.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to extrapolate out consequences like that, or you want your campaign to have magic closer to a hard magic system, then you should talk to your DM about it. Together, you can agree on certain rules for internal consistency, specific logical consequences of rules as written (RAW), or even strike down inconsistent things from RAW. No rule is immutable, as long as the DM agrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-dm-and-your-party-are-your-collaborators-not-your-enemies&quot;&gt;Your DM and your party are your collaborators, not your enemies!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;players-are-not-their-characters&quot;&gt;Players are not their characters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When playing &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; tabletop RPG, it’s extremely important to mentally separate the players from the player characters, and the NPCs from the DM. For an artificer, there is one especially important reason for this: You can surprise characters, but you should &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; surprise your DM or other players! (There are a few exceptions, but it must be done very, very carefully.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;roleplay-games-are-collaborative&quot;&gt;Roleplay games are collaborative&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roleplay games are a collaborative effort between everyone involved. Everyone is there to have fun and create an entertaining story. For it to remain fun for everyone, and especially for it to remain collaborative, all of the &lt;strong&gt;players&lt;/strong&gt; need to be in on the plan, with very few exceptions. It can be easy to assume that letting the other players know about the plan will take away the impact of your character’s brilliant on-the-spot improvisation, but I promise that it won’t. Besides, a brilliant improvisation involving the other people in your party can go so much farther!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provide-your-tools-to-the-party&quot;&gt;Provide your tools to the party&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to the topic of playing artificer, there are a few specific reasons you want everyone to be clued in. First, you want your shenanigans to be cleared with the DM before you enact them. Having to stop and wait for your DM to approve your shenanigans, or worse, arguing with them about it, can be a real mood killer. Secondly, &lt;strong&gt;your tools are not just for you!&lt;/strong&gt; As an artificer, your job is to provide your tools &lt;em&gt;to the party!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your job is to provide additional methods of problem solving to the party, and they can’t use them if they don’t know what they are. Additionally, telling your party about your tools lifts the burden of being the one who has to remember when to use them. If only you know about your tools, you have to be constantly alert for opportunities to use them. Informing your party lets them make use of your abilities in situations or ways that even you may not have thought to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="dnd" /><category term="ttrpg" /><category term="meta" /><summary type="html">In DnD 5e, Artificer has one of the loosest job descriptions of any class. Depending on both your playstyle and your DM’s, this can lend incredible flexibility or cause a decent amount of strife. To ensure things go as smoothly as they can, there are a few things you should keep in mind.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">List of Deep Rock Galactic Incidents</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/24/DRG_Incidents.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="List of Deep Rock Galactic Incidents" /><published>2022-05-24T19:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-05-24T19:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/24/DRG_Incidents</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/24/DRG_Incidents.html">&lt;p&gt;Working with the Deep Rock Galactic mining company is relatively safe. [Citation Needed] Here’s a list of the times it wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karl’s Demise&lt;/strong&gt; - [INFORMATION REDACTED]&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Adeptus Custodes Incident&lt;/strong&gt; - One salvage team was so intent on learning about the Adeptus Custodes that they forgot about the extraction timer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandblasted Hell Extraction&lt;/strong&gt; - Mission Control made a teeny weeny, itsy bitsy, 35% accuracy error when placing the drop pod. Long story short, it ended up perched on a sky-high ledge, and the team was forced to climb from the depths of the sandblasted corridors to make it to LZ. They made a heroic effort, but were unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 8-dwarf industrial sabotage&lt;/strong&gt; - 8 brave dwarves embarked upon one of our most dangerous industrial sabotage missions. Unfortunately, the rival technology detected the unusual number of dwarves, and sent reinforcements. The mission was absolute chaos, the team ran out of nitra, and ultimately did not survive. This is why we only send 4 dwarves at a time now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="video-games" /><category term="drg" /><category term="shitpost" /><summary type="html">Working with the Deep Rock Galactic mining company is relatively safe. [Citation Needed] Here’s a list of the times it wasn’t.</summary></entry></feed>